Anthony Lewis Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part II: Annual File, 1949-2007 (Box II:1-843)
  - 1949-1965 (Box II:1)
    - Gideon's Trumpet (Box II:3)
      - Business matters, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, (3 folders)
      - Reviews, (3 folders)
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Habeas corpus, (2 folders) (Box II:4)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., (2 folders)
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Insanity
    - "I-J" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy family
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Law column
    - Loyalty and security
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Mallory v. United States
    - Martha's Vineyard, Mass. (Box II:5)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New World Foundation
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Obscenity, (2 folders)
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Portrait of a Decade: The Second American Revolution
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Reapportionment, (4 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Saturday Evening Post (Box II:6)
    - Speeches
      - 1958-1961, (6 folders)
      - 1962, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:7)
      - 1963-1964, (8 folders)
    - Supreme Court
      - Attacks by Congress and others, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box II:8)
      - Background information, (2 folders)
      - Calendar
      - General, (4 folders)
      - Justices (Box II:9)
        - Black, Hugo L.
        - Brennan, William J.
        - Clark, Tom C.
        - Douglas, William O., (2 folders)
        - Frankfurter, Felix, (4 folders)
        - General
        - Goldberg, Arthur J.
        - Harlan, John M.
        - Recess appointments, (2 folders) (Box II:10)
        - Retired
        - Stewart, Potter
        - Warren, Earl, (2 folders)
        - White, Bryon R.
      - Notes, October terms 1963-1964, (5 folders)
    - "S-V" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:11)
    - Wiretapping
    - "W-Y" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1966
    - Martha's Vineyard, Mass.
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New World Foundation, (5 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:12)
    - "N-O" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "Projects"
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Random House
    - Rhodesia, (4 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Scandinavia (Box II:13)
    - Scotland, (2 folders)
    - Speeches
    - "S-T" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - University of Sussex, Brighton, England, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:14)
    - "U-V" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Wales
    - Wilson, Harold
    - "W" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1967
    - American Newspaper Guild
    - Austria
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - British Broadcasting Corp.
    - Brown, George Alfred, Baron, (2 folders)
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous
    - "Capital book"
    - Chichester, Sir Francis (Box II:15)
    - Correspondent's kit
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "'D' notices", (2 folders)
    - Ditchley Foundation, (2 folders)
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Fair trial and free press (Box II:16)
    - Foreign Press Association
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass., (3 folders)
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Institute of Journalists, London, England, (2 folders)
    - Italy
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - "J" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:17)
    - Kosygin, Alexei
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Last Exit to Brooklyn
    - Law
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Martha's Vineyard, Mass., (2 folders)
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New World Foundation, (1 folder); (8 folders) (Box II:18)
    - New York Times (Box II:19)
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Pensions
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Queen Elizabeth Hall, London, England
    - Random House
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Science
    - Scotland
    - The Second American Revolution: A First Hand Account of the Struggle for Civil Rights, (2 folders)
    - Sicily
    - Speeches, (2 folders)
    - Supreme Court
    - "S" miscellaneous
    - Torrey Canyon (oil tanker) (Box II:20)
    - Town and Country Planning Association
    - "T-V" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Wilson, Harold
    - "W-Y" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1968
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - British Broadcasting Corp.
    - Burgess, Anthony, (2 folders)
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Canonbury House, London, England
    - "Capital book" (Box II:21)
    - Century Association
    - Cornwall
    - Crime
    - "C" miscellaneous
    - Demonstrations
    - Ditchley Foundation, (4 folders)
    - "D" miscellaneous (Box II:22)
    - Edinburgh International Festival, (2 folders)
    - Expense statements
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Fair trial and free press
    - Fulbright program
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - Grove Primary School, Wolverhampton, England
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - "H" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:23)
    - Immigration, (3 folders)
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy, John F., assassination, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., (4 folders)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:24)
    - Law
    - "L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Martha's Vineyard, Mass.
    - Moore, Henry
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New World Foundation, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:25)
    - New York Times
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization See also Classified, (3 folders)
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Obscenity, (2 folders)
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Paris peace talks (Box II:26)
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Race, (2 folders)
    - Random House
    - Reston, James
    - Rhodesia, (2 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - The Second American Revolution: A First Hand Account of the Struggle for Civil Rights
    - Soviet Union (Box II:27)
    - Speeches
    - Supreme Court
    - Sweden, (2 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Tynan, Kenneth, and John Treveylan debate about censorship, (2 folders)
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - United States-United Kingdom Education Commission (Box II:28)
    - Vietnam
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Warren, Earl, article, (4 folders)
    - Wilson, Harold, lawsuit
    - Wilton Park, Sussex, England
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - 1969
    - Africa, trip, (2 folders)
    - Architecture (Box II:29)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Baker, Russell
    - Books
    - British Broadcasting Corp., (2 folders)
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Canonbury House, London, England
    - Century Association
    - Commonwealth Prime Minister's Conference, London, England
    - Constitution, British
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:30)
    - Devon, England
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Europe, (2 folders)
    - Expense statements
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Foreign press
    - Fortas, Abe
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - Gifts
    - Greece
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., (1 folder) (Box II:31)
    - "H" miscellaneous
    - Ireland, (3 folders)
    - Israel
    - "I-J" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy, Edward M.
    - Kennedy, Robert F.
    - "K" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:32)
    - Law
    - Libel
    - Lundy Island, England
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Martha's Vineyard, Mass.
      - Airport, (2 folders)
      - General, (2 folders)
    - Moon landing
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:33)
    - New York Times, (2 folders)
    - Nigeria
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Obscenity
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Press, (2 folders)
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Queen Elizabeth 2 (ship)
    - Race, (2 folders)
    - Random House (Box II:34)
    - Ray, James Earl, trial, (3 folders)
    - Reston, James
    - Royalty
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Speeches
    - Sweden
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Television
    - Turkey (Box II:35)
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - United States-United Kingdom Education Commission, (3 folders)
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Vietnam War, (2 folders)
    - Warren, Earl, (2 folders)
    - Wilson, Harold
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders) (Box II:36)
  - 1970
    - Africa, (4 folders)
    - Annenberg, Walter H.
    - "A" miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:37)
    - Baker, Russell
    - Books
    - Broadcasting, (2 folders)
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Century Association
    - Constitution
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Defense
    - Disarmament
    - Drugs
    - "D" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:38)
    - Environment, (2 folders)
    - Europe
    - "E-F" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - "H" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Immigration (Box II:39)
    - Institute for Strategic Studies, London, England
    - Ireland
    - "I-J" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy, Edward M.
    - Kennedy, Robert F.
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Labor
    - "L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:40)
    - National trust
    - New York Times
    - Nigeria
      - General
      - Trip, (2 folders)
    - Nobel Prize
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Obscenity
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Parliament, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:41)
    - Planning
    - Press, (2 folders)
    - "P" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Race
    - Random House
    - Reston, James
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Saint Katharine Docks, London, England
    - Scandinavia
    - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr
    - Speeches, (1 folder) (Box II:42)
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - "S-T" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - United States, trip
    - United States-United Kingdom Education Commission, (2 folders)
    - Universities
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Vietnam War, (3 folders) (Box II:43)
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Wilson, Harold
    - "W-Y" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
  - 1971
    - Africa, (2 folders)
    - Airport, London, England, proposed
    - Aldeburgh, England
    - America
    - American Bar Association, (1 folder) (Box II:44)
    - Architecture
    - "A" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Berrigan, Philip F., (2 folders)
    - Black, Hugo L.
    - Books, (2 folders)
    - British Broadcasting Corp.
    - Broadcasting
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:45)
    - Century Association
    - The Commonwealth
    - Concorde, (2 folders)
    - Crime
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Decimal currency
    - Dollar
    - Drugs
    - "D" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "E" miscellaneous (Box II:46)
    - Fair trial and free press
    - "F" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Heath, Edward, (2 folders)
    - "H" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Immigration
    - Incomes policy
    - Institute for Strategic Studies, London, England, (2 folders)
    - Ireland
    - "I" miscellaneous (Box II:47)
    - Jenkins, Roy
    - "J" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Kennedy family
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Law
    - "L" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Monetary
    - "M" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - New York Times
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Obscenity (Box II:48)
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Pakistan
    - Pentagon Papers
    - Portugal
    - Press
    - Prisons
    - Privacy
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Race
    - Random House
    - Rhodesia
      - Background information
      - Columns
      - Notes and cuttings
      - Official documents and guidebooks (Box II:49)
    - Rosenthal, A. M.
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Scandinavia
    - Soviet Union
    - Speeches
      - General
      - Roberts, Owen J., lecture, (3 folders)
    - Spies
    - Stein, Andrew, bill about aircraft noise standards
    - Supreme Court
    - "S" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:50)
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - United States, trip
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wis., (2 folders)
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Venice
    - Vietnam War, (5 folders)
    - "V" miscellaneous (Box II:51)
    - Wexford Festival
    - Wilson, Harold, (2 folders)
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - 1972
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Black, Hugo L.
    - Books, (2 folders)
    - British Broadcasting Corp.
    - Broadcasting, personal, (2 folders)
    - Busing, (2 folders) (Box II:52)
    - Bylines, (2 folders)
    - "B" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Canonbury House, London, England, preservation, (2 folders)
    - Century Association
    - China
    - Common Market, (4 folders) (Box II:53)
    - Concorde
    - Correspondent's kit
    - Crime, (2 folders)
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Devlin, Bernadette (Box II:54)
    - Ditchley Foundation, (2 folders)
    - Drugs
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Economy
    - Education
    - "E-F" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Law School Visiting Committee, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:55)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Heath, Edward
    - "H" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - India and Pakistan
    - Institute for Strategic Studies, London, England
    - Ireland, (2 folders)
    - "I" miscellaneous
    - Jenkins, Roy
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy, Edward M.
    - Kennedy, Robert F. (Box II:56)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Law, (3 folders)
    - "L-M" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - New York Times, (2 folders)
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - "O" miscellaneous (Box II:57)
    - Politics, (2 folders)
    - Press, (2 folders)
    - "P" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Race
    - Rhodesia
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Salzburg Seminar in American Studies, Salzburg, Austria
    - Security
    - Shalit, Nancy
    - Speeches
    - Supreme Court
    - Surroundings, (4 folders) (Box II:58)
    - Sweden, trip, (2 folders)
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - "T" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:59)
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Vietnam War
      - Columns by Lewis
      - Crimes, (5 folders)
      - Dikes
      - General, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box II:60)
      - Photographs
      - Prisoners, (2 folders)
      - Stockholm reports (Box II:61)
      - Vietnam trip, (6 folders)
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Welfare
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
  - 1973 (Box II:62)
    - Amnesty
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Books
    - Broadcasting
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Cambodia
    - Capital punishment, (2 folders)
    - Censorship (Box II:63)
    - Century Association
    - Conference on Government Secrecy, New York, N.Y., (5 folders); (2 folders) (Box II:64)
    - Crime
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Defense
    - Disarmament
    - "D" miscellaneous (Box II:65)
    - Economics
    - Energy, (2 folders)
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Food, (2 folders)
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - Great Britain (Box II:66)
    - Grenville Clark Fund, (2 folders)
    - Growth
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Crimson
    - Harvard Law School Visiting Committee, (2 folders)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass. (Box II:67)
    - "H-J" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Kennedy, Robert F.
    - Kissinger, Henry
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Law
    - "L" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:68)
    - Medical
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - New York Times
    - Nixon, Richard M.
    - North Atlantic Treaty Organization
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Oil
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Politics
    - Press, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:69)
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Race
    - Random House
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Shalit, Nancy
    - Shipping
    - Soviet Union (Box II:70)
    - Speeches, (3 folders)
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders)
    - Surroundings
    - "S-T" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box II:71)
    - USSR-US Seminar, Tallinn, Estonia, (3 folders)
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Vera Institute of Justice, New York, N.Y.
    - Vietnam War
      - General, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box II:72)
      - Prisoners, (1 folder) (Box II:73)
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Watergate
      - Burr, Aaron, case
      - Cox, Archibald, (2 folders)
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Impeachment, (1 folder) (Box II:74)
      - Saxbe, William B.
      - Special election
      - Special prosecutor
      - Taxes, (2 folders)
      - Watergate as Symbol Conference, Mount Kisco, N.Y.
    - "W-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1974
    - Amnesty
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box II:75)
    - Busing
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Capital punishment, (2 folders)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, (2 folders) (Box II:76)
    - Chile
    - China
    - Clubs, (2 folders)
    - Committee for Public Justice
    - Courts
    - Crime
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Defense and disarmament
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Economy
    - Energy, (7 folders) (Box II:77)
    - "E" miscellaneous (Box II:78)
    - Food, (5 folders)
    - Foreign policy
    - "F" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:79)
    - Gideon's Trumpet
    - Great Britain
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Trip, (2 folders)
    - Growth, (4 folders)
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:80)
    - Harvard Crimson
    - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass., (3 folders)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.
    - "H-I" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Justice Department
    - "J" miscellaneous
    - Kennedy, Edward M.
    - Kennedy, John F.
    - Kennedy, Robert F.
    - Kissinger, Henry, (3 folders) (Box II:81)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Law
    - Legal Action Center, New York, N.Y.
    - "L" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:82)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - New York Times
    - Nieman Foundation
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - Obscenity
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Politics
    - Population
    - Press
      - Branzburg v. Hayes
      - General
      - Miami Herald Publishing Co. v. Tornillo, (1 folder) (Box II:83)
      - Nixon, Richard M., papers, (2 folders)
      - Pentagon Papers, (3 folders)
      - Red Lion Broadcasting Co. (television access), (1 folder) (Box II:84)
    - "P-Q" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Race, (2 folders)
    - Random House
    - Richardson, Elliot L.
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., (2 folders)
    - "R" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Soviet Union, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:85)
    - Speeches
      - Jan.-Oct., (9 folders)
      - Nov., (2 folders) (Box II:86)
    - Supreme Court, (5 folders)
    - Sweden
    - "S" miscellaneous, (6 folders) (Box II:87)
    - Television
    - "T-U" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Vietnam War
      - General, (1 folder); (7 folders) (Box II:88)
      - Prisoners, (3 folders) (Box II:89)
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Watergate
      - Burr, Aaron, case
      - Campaign spending
      - Columns by Lewis, (2 folders)
      - Congressional committee proceedings, (2 folders)
      - Cox, Archibald, (2 folders) (Box II:90)
      - Ervin, Sam J., Jr.
      - Executive privilege, (2 folders)
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Impeachment, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:91)
      - Jaworski, Leon
      - Nixon, Richard M.
        - General, (2 folders)
        - Papers, (2 folders)
        - Resignation
      - Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:92)
      - St. Clair, James D., (2 folders)
      - Tapes
      - Taxes, (4 folders)
    - Trials, (2 folders) (Box II:93)
    - Wiretapping
    - "W" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
  - 1975
    - Africa
      - General
      - Rhodesia
      - South Africa, trip, (7 folders) (Box II:94)
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box II:95)
    - Bickel, Alexander M.
    - Busing
    - Bylines
    - "B" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - Cambodia (Box II:96)
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Mayagüez (container ship)
    - Capital punishment
    - Central Intelligence Agency, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:97)
    - Chile, (2 folders)
    - Crime, (2 folders)
    - Crossman, R. H. S., (6 folders) (Box II:98)
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Defense and disarmament
    - Douglas, William O. (Box II:99)
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Economy
    - Energy, (3 folders)
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation
    - Food, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:100)
    - Ford, Gerald R., (2 folders)
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Great Britain, (2 folders)
    - Grenville Clark Fund, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:101)
    - Growth
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Crimson
    - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass.
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass, (2 folders)
    - Human rights, (2 folders) (Box II:102)
    - "H-J" miscellaneous, (4 folders)
    - Katzenbach, Nicholas deB.
    - Kennedy, Edward M., and John F. Kennedy
    - Kennedy, Robert F.
    - Kissinger, Henry, (2 folders) (Box II:103)
    - "K" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Law
    - Legal Action Center, New York, N.Y.
    - Lippman, Walter
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Medical news
    - Middle East, (1 folder) (Box II:104)
    - "M" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - New York Times
    - Nieman Foundation
    - "N" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Ozone
    - "O" miscellaneous
    - Philippines
    - Politics, (1 folder) (Box II:105)
    - Press
      - Branzburg v. Hayes
      - Fairness doctrine
      - Freedom of Information Act, (2 folders)
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Great Britain, (1 folder) (Box II:106)
      - Libel and privacy, (6 folders)
      - Pentagon Papers, (5 folders) (Box II:107)
      - Press Censorship Newsletter
      - Press Council, (2 folders)
      - United States v. Dickinson, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box II:108)
      - United States v. Marchetti
      - S. 1, Criminal Justice Reform Act, (4 folders)
    - "P-Q" miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box II:109)
    - Race
    - Random House
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A.
    - "R" miscellaneous
    - Speeches
      - General, (5 folders); (3 folders) (Box II:110)
      - University of Utah, Salt Lake City, Utah, (2 folders)
    - Soviet Union, (3 folders)
    - Supreme Court, (2 folders) (Box II:111)
    - Surroundings
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Televison
    - "T-U" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Vietnam War, (3 folders); (4 folders) (Box II:112)
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Watergate
      - Executive privilege, (2 folders)
      - Freedman, Monroe H., and James D. St. Clair, (2 folders)
      - General
      - Glasser, Ira, and James D. St. Clair
      - Nixon, Richard, (2 folders) (Box II:113)
      - Pardon, (3 folders)
      - Special prosecutor
      - St. Clair, James D.
    - Wiretapping
    - "W" miscellaneous, (1 folder) (Box II:114)
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
  - 1976
    - Africa
      - Angola, (2 folders)
      - South Africa, (5 folders)
    - "A" miscellaneous
    - Bicentennial, (2 folders) (Box II:115)
    - Busing, (2 folders)
    - Bylines, (2 folders)
    - "B" miscellaneous, (3 folders)
    - California, trip
    - Cambodia (Box II:116)
      - General
      - Mayagüez (container ship)
    - Central Intelligence Agency
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Legislation
      - Schorr, Daniel
    - Chapel Market, London, England, (3 folders)
    - Chile, (2 folders) (Box II:117)
    - Concorde, (3 folders)
    - Courts, (2 folders)
    - Cox, Archibald
    - Crime, (2 folders)
    - "C" miscellaneous, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box II:118)
    - Defense and disarmament
    - "D" miscellaneous
    - Economy
    - Energy
    - "E" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation
    - Food
    - Ford, Gerald
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Great Britain
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Trip, (3 folders) (Box II:119)
    - Grenville Clark Fund, (2 folders)
    - "G" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Crimson